Shakti Shankar Mandal

UI Developer

Having 11+ years of experience on front end product development, I have not only proven myself by building complex and scalable applications throughout the career but also strengthen and broaden my technical skills for the future. Currently looking for a new opportunity to excel my career on UI Development.

\searrow

shaktishankarmandal@gmail.



7550181120



Hyderabad, India



23 April, 1988

linkedin.com/in/ShaktiShanka rMandal

github.com/s2304

SKILLS



react.js



reactive programing



WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. UI Developer

Cognizant technology solutions

03/2018 - Present

chennai

- Accomplishment/responsibilities
- As a senior developer, responsible for developing highly scalable, reactive and responsive product such as trading application with multiple commodities, banking.
- Building reusable code and libraries using JavaScript to build a better framework.
- Lead team to move windows application to web using react.js, C# and WPF
- Achieved significant improvement (~ 5-10%) on the application performance.
- Helped the client to reduce the workload (around 20%) from their internal user after migrating the application to web.
- Analyzing initial requirements to find out technical feasibility and impact on existing application
- Designing/prototyping high quality mock ups to provide an high level overview of the user interface to the user.
- Supervise software workflow management with project management tool(example Git, Jira, Sonar).
- Mentoring new team member about the product and the technologies.
- Perform code review and writing test case to follow TDD approach.

IT Analyst

Tata consultancy services

05/2010 - 03/2018

chennai

- Accomplishment/responsibilities
- Built multiple web portal using react and redux for company's internal activities.
- Part of the team to develop rest API using nodejs.
- Developed asynchronous and reactive application using TPL(Task parallel library) and rx.net.
- Played lead role for a banking migration project from WinForm to WPF.
- Groomed 6 members UI team for the migration project.
- Worked with business to prepare and come up with new requirement
- Prepared estimation of the change based on the requirement analysis.
- Developed unit testing cases using NUnit framework.

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Bengali

Full Professional Proficiency

Professional Working Proficiency

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Retail Karbar 🗹

 Retail karbar is an application which can be used in retail shop to track their sells, orders. Currently, hosted in heruko platform. Designed using react.js in the front end, node.js in the backend.

Bank Management System 🗹

" this is a banking application where user can register and apply for different kind of loans. Developed using angular and C#.

INTERESTS

photography

coocking

playing football

EDUCATION

Bachelor of technology Techno India College of Technology

07/2005 - 06/2009

Courses

Electronics and communication engineering

kolkata